# María José Barón

## BILINGUAL RECRUITER

+57 3209886940

maria.baron@solvoglobal.com

Bogotá, Colombia

# **ABOUT ME**

I'm mayor in Tourism and Hotel Business management, I also have a technician in payroll and social benefits. With experience on the customer service area for almost 5 years. I was in an internship for a Hilton hotel in different departments, so I had to be multitasking to improve many areas there. I'm a leader, with high communication skills, passionate and hard-working person. I'm a team worker and, also a problem-solver in order to work under pressure.

# BACKGROUND

**Business Management** 2016-2022

Universidad Externado de Colombia

Technician in payroll and social benefits 2014-2015

Instituto Nacional de Aprendizaje- SENA

## JOB EXPERIENCE

Bilingual Recruiter
Jul 2022 - Currently

Solvo Global

Recruitment and selection of human talent for companies in the United States through the management of social networks Internship under operation's department Apr 2021 - Oct 2021

Hotel DoubleTree by Hilton Salitre AR

Support the administrative processes related to front desk and quality departments. Supplier validation, night audit, brand standards and loyalty program.

Commercial and marketing consultant Feb 2016 - Nov 2019

Colombia Caribean Tropical Potatoes Ltda

Management assistant and commercial advisor.

Handling public relationships and event organization.

# SKILLS

#### Languages

- English level B2 (IELTS certification)
- Native Spanish
- Basic French

## Soft skills

- Time management
- Decision-making
- Leadership
- Communication skills
- Work ethic
- Problem-Solving
- Critical-Thinking
- Emphatic

## Hard Skills

- · Counseling and guidance
- $\bullet \quad Operations, \ and \ administrative process.$
- · Billing, invoices and payments process.
- Human Talent Management
- Recruitment and selection
- Profile analysis
- Interview skills